

Syed Shahin Ahmed

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a persevering individual who is aspiring to establish an identity in the I.T industry with progressive experience in the hospitality and retail sector. I am seeking to broaden my horizons after spending six years in hospitality and eagerly await the challenges ahead which will utilize my meticulous attention to detail and friendly, professional manner. With an enthusiastic attitude, I refuse to allow anyone to get in the way of my aims and objectives which are always aligned with that of the organization. I am a mature person who only focuses on the present task while I also create a pleasant atmosphere with the people I work with and the people I serve.

COMPETENCIES

- Customer service
- Effective time management
- Strong planning and organisational skills
- Self-Motivated
- Good Interpersonal Skills
- Good communication Skills
- Good leadership skills
- Hard-working

EXPERIENCE

10/06/2013 - 01/02/2016

Assistant Manager - Narangee

This was a role which saw me rise up through the ranks, initially starting out as a waiter who would communicate and greet customers, taking their order, delivering the order, collecting checks and answering and trying to fulfil additional queries and requests. After a period of 1 year, I was promoted to the assistant manager which gave me further responsibilities such as reconciliation of the cash drawers and in charge of the stock order as well as restocking. In order to decrease profit loss, we would effectively use the stock we have which lead to the overall decrease in waste. Demonstrated liability issues by confirming legal drinking age as well as conforming to the law and restricted serving to already intoxicated consumers. Resolving customer disputes in a calm and intelligent manner. Alongside the management team, we collaborated together to Improve the front-of-house-morale.

02/04/2012 - 13/05/2013

Bar Assistant - Bullshead Pub

This role involved being proactive in acknowledging and greeting customers entering into the bar. Mixed up various beverages to enhance client's satisfaction as well as offering advice on what to drink. I was also given the responsibility of keeping the bar clean along with restocking the inventory. I ensured that all cash, charge, float and till procedures were carried out in accordance with company policy. Also, regulated ID checks to comply with the law in ensuring people were of age to drink. Also refused serving more alcohol to guests who were intoxicated. Lead the bar closing duties by securing the building and leaving the place in a clean state.

03/01/2011 - 18/03/2012

Head Waiter - The Raj

This role involved being responsible for communicating with kitchen staff regarding customer allergies, dietary needs, and various queries. Accurately recorded orders and partnered with team members to serve food and beverages that exceeded guests' expectations. Inquired about guest satisfaction while also anticipating additional



EMAIL: SYEDSHAHINAHMED@ICLOUD.COM



MOBILE: 0830435694



ADDRESS: ATLANTIC HOUSE TURKEY ROAD, TRAMORE CO. WATERFORD

- Energetic
- Trustworthy
- Value individuality, opportunity and respect
- Aptitude for working in a teambased environment
- Polite and helpful
- The ability to thrive in a highstress environment
- Ability to work overtime
- Passion for people
- Food industry knowledge
- Food safety knowledge
- Inventory
- Cash handling
- Advanced IT skills.

needs and happily fulfilling requests. Accepting payments from customers, giving change and receipts. Give Training and mentored new wait and host staff.

EDUCATION

Code Institute

• Full Stack Developer (Currently Studying)

Anglia Ruskin University

BA in Marketing

Shah Jalal College

• H.S.C (equivalent to A' level)

The Aided High School

• S.S.C (equivalent to O' level)

HOBBIES

I am a very active person who likes trying out new activities for both mindful stimulation and personal development. I am a keen sports enthusiast with a particular interest in football and tennis which have developed my physical conditioning, communication and teamworking skills.

I feel a great sense of accomplishment when I help people which is the fuel for my ambition to go into I.T so that I could develop my own programme which would immensely help others.

I am also very intrigued by learning about different cultures which is why I have the ambition to travel around the world and learn about the languages and cultures.

QUALIFICATIONS

I.T

- Full Stack Developer (Studying Online)
- C++ (Studying Online)
- Swift (Studying Online)
- Wireshark
- CCNA (Studying Online)
- Python (Studying Online)

REFERENCES

Available on request